A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office Files of Alison R. Bernstein FA573
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Vice President Files, 1974-2007; 6.08 Cubic Feet 16 letter document boxes
  - Law: Ford Foundation Grantees and the Pursuit of Justice, 2000 (Box 26, Folder 216)
  - Education, Media, Arts and Culture (EMAC) Retreat, The Nassau Inn, Princeton, New Jersey, 2001 (Box 26, Folder 217)
  - Women's Leadership, Gender and Peace (Report 015797), 2001 (Box 26, Folder 218)
  - The Ford Foundation 1952-2002: Celebrating 50 Years of Partnership, India, Nepal, Sri Lanka (Box 26, Folder 219)
- Executive Officer Subject Files, 1975-2010; 22.38 Cubic Feet 58 containers
  - Field Office Chronological Files - Ruth Mayleas Explanatory Memo, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 220)
  - Field Office Chronological Files - Bangladesh Office, 1991-1992 (Box 26, Folder 221)
  - Field Office Chronological Files - Cairo/Khartoum Office, 1991-1992 (Box 26, Folder 222)
  - Field Office Chronological Files - China Office, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 223)
  - Field Office Chronological Files - India Office, 1991-1992 (Box 26, Folder 224)
  - Field Office Chronological Files - Indonesia Office, 1992-1995 (Box 26, Folder 225)
  - Field Office Chronological Files - Rio Office, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 226)
  - Education and Culture - Alison Bernstein's Chronological Files A-Z, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 227-229, Box 28, Folder 230)
    A-R - Box 27
    S-Z - Box 28
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence To/From Director, 1993-1994 (Box 28, Folder 231-233)
  - Education and Culture - General Files, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 234, Box 29, Folder 235-236)
    Organized alphabetically
  - Staff Meetings, 1991-1994 (Box 29, Folder 237)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence United States International Affairs Program (USIAP)/Office of Vice President (OVP) (Berresford, Gaberman, Jaffe, Duggan), 1994 (Box 29, Folder 238)
  - Ruth Mayleas - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 239)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Media - Andrea Taylor, 1992-1994 (Box 30, Folder 240)
  - Education and Culture - Field Office - Africa, 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 241)
  - Education and Culture - Field Office - Asia, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 242)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence To/From President Thomas and Chairman Schact, 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 243)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence - Trustees Information, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 244)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence - Office of Communications, 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 245)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence - Interoffice, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 246)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence (Timothy J. Bork, et al) - Africa and the Middle East, New York Program, 1994 (Box 30, Folder 247)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence - Asia Program (New York) (Geithner et al.), 1993-1994 (Box 30, Folder 248)
  - Education and Culture - Latin America and the Caribbean (Dassin et al.), 1994 (Box 30, Folder 249)
  - Education and Culture - Field Offices - Latin America, 1991-1993 (Box 30, Folder 250)
  - Retreats - Urban Poverty and Education and Culture, 1994 November-December (Box 30, Folder 251)
  - Western Interstate Commission for Higher Education (WICHE)/Faculty Diversity Meeting, 1995 (Box 30, Folder 252)
  - Special Projects and General Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 30, Folder 253)
  - Education and Culture Staff Meetings, 1994-1995 (Box 31, Folder 254)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - South Africa, 1992-1994 (Box 31, Folder 255)
  - Education and Culture - Urban Public Education Reform Seminars, 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 256)
  - Education and Culture - Bellagio Africa Cultural Meeting, The Rockefeller Foundation, 1995 February (Box 31, Folder 257)
  - Education and Culture - Fellowship Communication Evaluation, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 258)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Diversity Cases, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 259)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Diversity and Faculty, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 260)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Desegregating Higher Education, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 261)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Beijing Conference, 1995 (Box 32, Folder 262)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - 1995 Biennial Program Review, 1994-1995 (Box 32, Folder 263)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Campus Diversity - India (David Arnold) (949-0003), 1993-1995 (Box 32, Folder 264)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - African Studies (Biddle/Bork), 1994-1995 (Box 32, Folder 265)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - International Studies, 1992-1993 (Box 32, Folder 266)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Historical 1992 and 1993 Biennial Budget, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 267)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Donors Educational Collaborative (Susan Berresford and Other Foundations), 1992-1996 (Box 32, Folder 268, Box 33, Folder 269-272)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Latin America Gender Studies (Cynthia Sanborn), 1992 (Box 33, Folder 273)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Latin America Area Studies (Joan Dassin/Shep Forman), 1993 (Box 34, Folder 274)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Native Americans Task Force, 1992-1993 (Box 34, Folder 275)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Paraprofessional in Education (Anna Lou Pickett/Grad Center), 1993 (Box 34, Folder 276)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Affirmative Action, 1995 (Box 34, Folder 277)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - American Council of Learned Societies (ACLS), 1992 (Box 34, Folder 278)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - American Social History Project (ASHP) Hunter College, CUNY (Stephen Brier), 1992 (Box 34, Folder 279)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Columbia University (Bob Pollack), 1988-1994 (Box 34, Folder 280)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Committee for International Academic Freedom, 1992-1994 (Box 34, Folder 281)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Defense Conversion Committee, June Zeitlin et al., 1994 (Box 34, Folder 282)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Michigan Partnership for New Education, 1992 (Box 34, Folder 283)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - University of Natal (Brenda Grouly), 1994-1995 (Box 34, Folder 284)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Para-Educators, Pickett, Anna Lou, 1993 (Box 34, Folder 285)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Social Science Research Council, 1994 (Box 35, Folder 286)
  - Education and Culture - Program Review, 1993 (Box 35, Folder 287)
  - Education and Culture - Program Review - Oversize Planning Documents (Folder 729)
  - Education and Culture - Work File - Arts Program Paper, 1993-1994 (Box 35, Folder 288)
  - Education and Culture - Desk File - Director's Group (Education and Youth Program), 1995 (Box 35, Folder 289)
  - Institute of International Education (IIE) Meeting, 1995 December 4 (Box 35, Folder 290)
  - Southern Education Foundation Meeting at Ford Foundation, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 291)
  - Desk File - Developing Country Programs (DCP) Area/Women's Studies, 1992-1993 (Box 36, Folder 292)
  - Southern Education Foundation's Briefing, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 293)
  - Letters, Buck Slips, Memos, Telephone Notes etc., 1993 (Box 36, Folder 294)
  - Education and Culture Meetings, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 295)
  - Education and Culture Correspondence - To/From Director, 1996 (Box 36, Folder 296-297)
  - Alison Bernstein's Chronological Files A-Z, 1995 (Box 37, Folder 298-299)
  - Education and Culture General Files (A-Z), 1996 (Box 37, Folder 300)
  - Education and Culture - Correspondence To/From President (Susan Berresford), 1996 (Box 38, Folder 301)
  - Blacks and the Mass Media: The Reasons for Action, the Actions to Take, Nolan A. Bowie (Fellow, Aspen Institute Program on Communications and Society) (Ford Foundation Funded), 1996 (Box 38, Folder 302)
  - South Africa, Mozambique Trip, 1992-1994 (Box 38, Folder 303)
  - Correspondence and Proposals, 1991-1994 (Box 38, Folder 304-305)
  - Partnership for National Service - Making AmeriCorps Stronger, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 306)
  - Material for the Trustee Budget Paper, 1996-1998 (Box 38, Folder 307)
  - Work File - Social Science Research Council - Archives/Rockefeller Archive Center, 1993-1995 (Box 39, Folder 308)
  - Work File - Royal Norwegian Embassy (Tore Li), 1995-1997 (Box 39, Folder 309)
  - Education and Culture - Work File - Public Information Project on Campus Diversity, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 310)
  - Work File - Cultural Dimensions of Natural Resource Management Workshop, 1995-1996 (Box 39, Folder 311)
  - Work File - Cultural Dimensions of Natural Resource Management, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 312)
  - Work File - Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences, Stanford, 1998 (Box 39, Folder 313)
  - Work File - Campus Diversity Initiative - Diversity in Higher Education Poll, News Conference, 1998 October 6 (Box 39, Folder 314)
  - Work File - Campus Diversity Initiative - Public Information File, 1995-1998 (Box 40, Folder 315)
  - Work File - American Museum of Natural History (Ellen Futter), 1996 August (Box 40, Folder 316)
  - Work File - 1996 Conference of Ford Fellows, Irvine, California, 1996 October (Box 40, Folder 317)
    Includes 1996 Directory of Ford Foundation Fellowships
  - Work File - National Research Council - Fellowships, 1995-1996 (Box 40, Folder 318)
  - Work File - Media and Public Policy (Times Mirror Center for the People and the Press, Andrew Kohut), 1994-1996 (Box 40, Folder 319-320)
  - Work File - Lincoln University, Barnes Foundation, Barnes Bond Connection, Blueprint 2000 (Niara Sudarkasa), 1994-1996 (Box 41, Folder 321)
  - Work File - Global Urban Research Initiative, 1995 (Box 41, Folder 322)
  - Desk File - Transition Planning - Susan Berresford, 1996-1997 (Box 41, Folder 323)
  - 1996 Board of Trustees Meeting and Overseas Program Review, 1995-1996 (Box 41, Folder 324)
  - September 1996 Board of Trustees Meeting (Box 41, Folder 325)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture December 1996 Committee Meeting and Board of Trustees Meeting (Box 41, Folder 326)
  - Information for Trustees Meeting, 1996 December 11-12 (Box 41, Folder 327)
  - Information for June 1996 Board of Trustees Meeting (Box 41, Folder 328)
  - Draft Executive Summary "Achieving Diversity in the Professoriate" EXECSUM4.DOC, S. Heath, 1996 May 15 (Box 41)
  - F. Report-Doc Appendi.doc (Box 41)
  - Ford Foundation Report Mac 501 (Microsoft Word), 1996 June 3 (Box 41)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1997 September (Box 41, Folder 329)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1997 June (Box 41, Folder 330)
  - Board of Trustees Meeting, 1997 March (Box 41, Folder 331)
  - Desk File - Women Writers, PEN American Center (Siobhan Dowd), 1994 (Box 41, Folder 332)
  - Office of Vice President - Work File - Arts Education (Young Audiences, New York), 1998 (Box 42, Folder 333)
  - Work File - Hopes on the Horizon (Henry Hampton), 1998-2001 (Box 42, Folder 334)
  - Work File - Double Take (Robert Coles), 1998 (Box 42, Folder 335)
  - Fleischman, Joel (Atlantic Philanthropic Service Company, Inc.), 1997 (Box 42, Folder 336)
  - Work File - Harvard University Graduate School of Education (Howard Gardner), 1997-1998 (Box 42, Folder 337)
  - Work File - The Hastings Center (Mark Hanson), 1996-1997 (Box 42, Folder 338)
  - Work File - Institute on Arts and Civil Dialogue (Harvard/Yale/Stanford Proposals), 1997 (Box 42, Folder 339)
  - Learning Media Limited - Consultants' Report (David Hargreaves), 1997 (Box 43, Folder 340-341)
  - Broadcasting and Adult Literacy, Third World General, India, Kenya, Mexico, David Hargreaves, 1997 July 5 (Box 43)
  - Office of the Vice President - Library of Congress/National Digital Library, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 342)
  - Work File - Mashantucket Pequot Museum and Research Center, Steve Dennin, 1997 (Box 43, Folder 343)
  - Office of the Vice President - Work File - Media Lab, 1998 (Box 43, Folder 344)
  - Work File - Microsoft Corporation (Barbara Dingfield), 1997 (Box 43, Folder 345)
  - Work File - National Endowment for the Humanities (Sheldon Hackney), 1995-1996 (Box 44, Folder 346)
  - Work File - National Foreign Language Center, David Maxwell, Toby Volkman, 1998 (Box 44, Folder 347)
  - Education and Culture - Work File - The Oxford Companion to American Military History Volume, 1995 (Box 44, Folder 348)
  - Work File - Robert Pollack Seminars (Columbia University), 1996 (Box 44, Folder 349)
  - Work File - Success for All Foundations (Sandler), 1998 (Box 44, Folder 350)
  - Work File - University of California President's Office, Oakland (Hardy Frye - Urban Committee - School Collaboration), 1991-1997 (Box 44, Folder 351)
  - Work File - University of California, Los Angeles/Proposition 209 (Adolfo Bermeo), 1997 (Box 45, Folder 352)
  - Biennial Program Review, 1994-2001 (Box 45, Folder 353)
  - Sub-Group in Culture and Education - Transition Planning, 1996 (Box 45, Folder 354)
  - International Fellowships Fund - Meetings of the Board of Directors, 2001-2003 (Box 45, Folder 355)
  - National Museum of American History (NMAH) Board Meetings, Washington D.C., 2000-2003 (Box 45, Folder 356, Box 46, Folder 357)
  - Commission on the Future of Independent Higher Education in Summit, New Jersey (Francis J. Mertz/James O'Boyle), 2001 (Box 46, Folder 358)
  - President's Advisory Board on Tribal Colleges and Universities (PABTCU), Washington, D.C., 1999-2000 (Box 46, Folder 359-360)
  - National Museum of American History - Board Meetings, Washington, D.C., 2003 (Box 47, Folder 361-362)
  - Smithsonian Institution - National Museum of American History - Campaign Funding Study Report, 2000 (Box 47, Folder 363)
  - Meeting of the Program Advisory Committee - International Fellowships Fund, 2002 November (Box 47, Folder 364-365)
  - Work File - Program Officer Orientation, 2002 (Box 48, Folder 366-367)
  - Work File - Cultural Institutions Group (Ellen Futter, George Wolfe, David McKinney et al.), 2001 (Box 48, Folder 368)
  - Office of the Vice President - Work File - Teacher Education Accreditation Council, 1999 (Box 48, Folder 369)
  - Work File - Southern Education Foundation (SEF), Lynn Huntley, 2001 (Box 48, Folder 370)
  - F.A. Thomas and Family, 1998 (Box 48, Folder 371)
  - Education, Arts, and Culture (EAC) Transition Planning Meeting, 1996 February 14 (Box 48, Folder 372)
  - Education, Arts, and Culture (EAC) Transition Planning, 1996 (Box 48, Folder 373, Box 49, Folder 374)
  - Partnership for National Service, 1993-1996 (Box 49, Folder 375)
  - National and Community Service Meetings and Panels, 1992-1993 (Box 49, Folder 376-377)
  - Desk File - Ford Foundation Steering Committee Business Resumption Plan, 1996-1999 (Box 49, Folder 378)
  - Desk file - Civic Education, 2000-2001 (Box 50, Folder 379)
  - Desk File - Ford Foundation Africa Higher Education, 1999 October (Box 50, Folder 380)
  - Office of the Vice President - Desk File - The Future of Eastern Europe Program, 2001 July (Box 50, Folder 381)
  - Desk File - Gender and Institutional Change Project, June Zeitlin, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 382)
  - Desk File - Ford Foundation Second Report of the On-Time Grantmaking Task Force, 2002 (Box 50, Folder 383)
  - Office of the Vice President/Education, Media, Arts, and Culture - Desk File - Ford Foundation President's Leadership, 1999 (Box 50, Folder 384)
  - Desk File - Ford Foundation - Project GRAD - MDRC, 2001-2002 (Box 50, Folder 385)
  - Office of the Vice President/Education, Media, Arts, and Culture - Desk File - Ford Foundation New Leaders, 1998-2001 (Box 50, Folder 386-387)
  - Creative Capital (Archibald Gillies), 2001 (Box 50, Folder 388)
  - Work File - Institute of International Education - Fulbright Program (David Arnold), 1999 (Box 51, Folder 389)
  - Desmond Tutu Reception, 2005 March 11 (Box 51, Folder 390)
  - The Desmond Tutu Peace Centre: An Invitation to Partner, undated; CD (Box 51)
  - The Desmond Tutu Peace Centre: Presents: Hands That Shape Humanity, undated; CD (Box 51)
  - Ford Foundation Immigration Grantmaking Index, 2001-2003 (Box 51, Folder 391)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) - Worldwide Meeting, 1999 January 4-8 (Box 51, Folder 392-393)
  - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) - 1998 Annual New York Programming Review Meeting, 1998 September 9-10 (Box 51, Folder 394)
  - Media and Communications at a Crossroads: The Role of Scholarship for Media Reform and Justice, Ford Foundation, New York, 2006 January 20 (Box 51, Folder 395)
  - Ford Foundation Grantmaking in Education in Latin America, 1962-2002, 2005 April (Box 52, Folder 396)
  - Anti-Defamation League: A World of Difference Institute - Peer Training Program (Meeting with Ford Foundation at Clara Barton High School), 2004 (Box 52, Folder 397)
  - National Museum American Indian (NMAI) - Opening - Correspondence and Pamphlets, Washington D.C., 2004-2005 (Box 52, Folder 398)
  - B'nai B'rith International Distinguished Achievement Award Honoring, Ratan Tata, St. Regis Hotel, New York City, 2005 May 23 (Box 52, Folder 399)
  - Social Science Research Council (SSRC) and Oxford Internet Institute Workshop, 2005 (Box 52, Folder 400)
  - Work File - Joint Program Worldwide Meeting, Santa Monica, California, 1998-2002 (Box 52, Folder 401)
  - Convening of the Media Arts and Culture Learning Group, Oakland, California, 2002 October 24-26 (Box 52, Folder 402)
  - Feminist Reverberations, Talk for Ford Foundation Joint Worldwide Meeting, Joan Wallach Scott, 2002 October 27 (Box 52, Folder 403)
  - Ford Foundation Joint Worldwide Meeting - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom (KCF) Program Sessions (9-12), 2002 October 27 (Box 52, Folder 404)
  - Peggy Antrobus Book Launch Invitation/Planning Correspondence, 2004-2005 (Box 52, Folder 405)
  - Joint Worldwide Meeting Correspondence and General Information, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 406)
    Includes Alison Bernstein's Meeting Keynote - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Program: What We Do and What Is To Be Done
  - Joint Worldwide Meeting Program Sessions Planning - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom (KCF) - San Francisco State University, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 407)
  - Joint Worldwide Meeting Program Sessions Planning - International Fellowships Program, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 408)
  - Ford Foundation Joint Worldwide Meeting - Schedule and Session Information, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 409)
  - Birzeit University Luncheon at Ford Foundation, 2001 November (Box 52, Folder 410)
  - Guest Lecturer, NYU Wagner Graduate School of Public Service Course, 2006 June (Box 53, Folder 411)
  - Ford Foundation Grantmaking and in Education in Latin America 1962 to 2002, 2005 April (Box 53, Folder 412)
  - National and Community Service Planning Meeting, Santa Monica, California, 1999 January 3-4 (Box 53, Folder 413)
  - Ford Foundation Education and Culture Program - Worldwide Workshop on Culture, Regional Overviews of Cultural Programming, Bamako, Mali and Dakar, Senegal, 1995 January 15-20 (Box 53, Folder 414)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program, All Staff Reflections, 2006 October (Box 53, Folder 415)
  - Knowledge, Creativity and Freedom Program Briefing Book Worldwide Meeting, Beijing/Guilin, China, 2006 October 8-13 (Box 53, Folder 416)
  - Ford Foundation, Education and Culture Program, Worldwide Workshop on Culture, Bamako, Mali, and Dakar, Senegal, 1995 January 15-20 (Box 54, Folder 417)
  - A Staff Guide to the Ford Foundation Archives: How We Can Help You, undated (Box 54, Folder 418)
  - Program Leadership Program, Ford Foundation, 2001 March (Box 54, Folder 419)
  - Learning Products Catalog, The Ford Foundation - Draft, 2001 March (Box 54, Folder 420)
  - Higher Education Summit - Plenary Lunch: What Does Multiculturalism Mean Today? Perspectives of Academic, Foundation, and Corporate Leaders, 2006 June (Box 54, Folder 421)
  - Vietnamese Delegation Luncheon at the Ford Foundation, 2003 September 10 (Box 54, Folder 422)
  - John Yochelson Meeting, 2004 (Box 54, Folder 423)
  - Politics of Inclusion Conference Keynote and Remarks, 2006 September 12 (Box 54, Folder 424)
  - Education Grantmaking by the Ford Foundation in Latin America: An Overview: A Report Submitted to the Ford Foundation, Nigel Brooke, 2004 December (Box 54, Folder 425)
  - Correspondence regarding Ruth Reardon, USA Committee for UNESCO, 2006 March (Box 54, Folder 426)
  - NYU Graduate Seminar, 2005 (Box 54, Folder 427)
  - Rights-Based Work in Vietnam Meeting at Ford Foundation Meeting, 2004 November (Box 54, Folder 428)
  - City College of New York, Charles B. Rangel Center on Public Service Grant Follow-Up and Presentation Invitation Luncheons, 2006-2007 (Box 54, Folder 429)
  - Peace Lessons from Around the World, Hague Appeal for Peace, 2006 April 11 (Box 55, Folder 430)
  - Opening Doors: Building Learning Communities: Early Results from the Opening Doors Demonstration at Kingsborough Community College, Dan Bloom and Colleen Sommo, MDRC, 2005 June (Box 55, Folder 431)
  - Opening Doors: Promoting Student Success in Community College and Beyond: The Opening Doors Demonstration, Thomas Brock and Allen LeBlanc, MDRC, 2005 May (Box 55, Folder 432)
  - The White House Conference on Global Literacy, New York Public Library, 2006 September 18 (Box 55, Folder 433)
  - Work File - Education and Culture Worldwide Meeting, 1987-1995 (Box 55, Folder 434-435)
  - Education and Culture Worldwide Meeting - Smithsonian Workshop - Evaluating Trends in the Collection, Preservation, and Dissemination of Traditional Music and Dance, 1993 (Box 56, Folder 436)
  - Memos and Correspondence, 1995-2000 (Box 56, Folder 437)
  - Desk File - Yolanda Moses, President, The City College of The City University of New York, 1999 (Box 56, Folder 438)
  - Project Pericles, 1998-2005 (Box 56, Folder 439-440)
  - Project Pericles Files - Reference Papers and Executive Planning Board Meeting Minutes - Eugene Lang, 2004-2007 (Box 56, Folder 441-442)
  - Conference of Periclean Presidents and Chairs at the Ford Foundation, 2004 December 1 (Box 57, Folder 443)
  - Foundations Presidents Meeting on Population and Reproductive Health, 2004 (Box 57, Folder 444)
  - David Coulson, Trust for African Rock Art (TARA) Meeting, 2006 May (Box 57, Folder 445)
  - He Huang, Chinese Primary School Principal, Beijing's Xingzhi School Meeting, 2007 (Box 57, Folder 446)
  - Carl Weisbrod/Fred Papert - Music and the Brain, 2006 (Box 57, Folder 447)
  - Complaint - University of So Paulo's Master's Course in Human Rights, 2005 (Box 57, Folder 448)
  - Council of Independent Colleges - Conversation Between Foundation Officers and College and University Presidents, 2004 (Box 57, Folder 449)
  - Rights-Based Work in Vietnam Meeting, 2004 (Box 57, Folder 450)
  - Mary Beth Salerno, President, American Express Foundation - Economic Independence Fund Grant - Request for Proposals, 2004 (Box 57, Folder 451)
  - Alaska Trip and Alaska Heritage Foundation Meeting at the Ford Foundation, 2005-2006 (Box 57, Folder 452)
  - Smolny College Project/Bard College, 2003 (Box 57, Folder 453)
  - Ford Foundation Schools and Communities Meeting, 2005 May 12 (Box 57, Folder 454)
  - Anna DeVare Smith - Let Me Down Easy - Africa Trip, 2005 (Box 57, Folder 455)
  - Knowledge, Creativity, and Freedom Retreats - Correspondence and Itineraries, 2004-2005 (Box 57, Folder 456-457)
  - Difficult Dialogues - "Academic Freedom Under Fire," Jonathan R. Cole - Daedalus, 2005-2006 (Box 57, Folder 458)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Clippings, 2005-2006 (Box 57, Folder 459-461)
  - Difficult Dialogues - American Association of University Professors - Statements, 2006 (Box 57, Folder 462)
  - Difficult Dialogues - Clippings, Ford Letter on Academic Freedom, and Request for Proposals, 2005-2006 (Box 57, Folder 463)
    Difficult Dialogues: Promoting Pluralism and Academic Freedom on Campus, A Letter from Susan V. Berresford and Selected Higher Education Leaders